Now as we discussed earlier,
الآن، كما ناقشنا سابقًا،
let's look at the different channels available to find new clients whom you can work for.
هيا نلقي نظرة على القنوات المختلفة المتاحة للعثور على عملاء جدد يمكنك العمل معهم.
First and foremost, social media has always been
أولاً وقبل كل شيء، لطالما كانت وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي
a popular revenue to find new people for personal as well as professional purposes.
مصدرًا شائعًا للعثور على أشخاص جدد للأغراض الشخصية والمهنية.
For digital freelancing as well,
للعمل الحر الرقمي أيضًا،
it is no different.
لا يوجد فرق.
One can find new clients by just posting about
يمكن للمرء أن يجد عملاء جدد فقط عن طريق النشر
their availability to work on projects in their area of expertise.
بخصوص تطلعهم للعمل في مشاريع في مجال خبرتهم.
Even clients use these platforms to advertise
حتى العملاء يستخدمون هذه المنصات للإعلان
their requirements in order to find freelancers to work on their projects.
متطلباتهم من أجل العثور على مترجمين للعمل على مشاريعهم.
Another and one of the most popular revenues for
آخر مكان وأشهرهم
freelancers to find clients are freelancing platforms.
العثور على العملاء من خلال منصات العمل الحر.
These platforms are marketplaces that are specifically
هذه المنصات هي الأسواق التي هي على وجه التحديد
designed for clients and freelancers to find each other.
مصممة للعملاء وأصحاب الأعمال الحرة للعثور على بعضهم البعض.
They not only help with discovery but also help with payments and in disputes, etc.
إنهم لا يساعدون في الاكتشاف فحسب، بل يساعدون أيضًا في المدفوعات والنزاعات، وما إلى ذلك.
Because of the importance of freelancing platforms in the freelancing world,
نظرًا لأهمية منصات العمل الحر في عالم العمل الحر،
you will see us diving deeper into them later in this lesson.
سترانا نتعمق أكثر فيها لاحقًا في هذا الدرس.
Yet another important channel is your own network.
قناة أخرى مهمة هي شبكتك الخاصة.
Now by networks here,
الآن عن طريق الشبكات هنا،
we mean your friends,
نقصد أصدقائك
family, ex-colleagues whom you already know.
العائلة والزملاء السابقين الذين تعرفهم بالفعل.
It is often said that it is easier to find a full-time job when you tap your network.
غالبًا ما يُقال أنه من الأسهل العثور على وظيفة بدوام كامل عند البحث في شبكتك.
Even in the freelancing world,
حتى في عالم العمل الحر،
you'll see that your network could play
سترى أن شبكتك يمكن أن تلعب
a great role in getting you new clients through referrals.
دور كبير في الحصول على عملاء جدد من خلال الإحالات.